Dalbir Singh

WEB DEVELOPER



+1-236-987-8514



Malbirsrana@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/dalbirsrana



github.com/dalbirsrana



dalbirsrana.github.io

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, ReactJS, jQuery, MySQL, GitHub

EDUCATION

Post Degree Diploma in Web & Mobile App Development Graduated in 2020

Langara College,

Vancouver, BC, Canada

Master of Science in Information Technology Graduated in 2006

Panjab University, Chandigarh, INDIA

ABOUT ME

Web developer with 5 years of experience in building high performing, user-friendly responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and PHP as well as working knowledge of ReactJS library. Up to date on best web practices, SEO principles and Agile development methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

- Led and collaborate in the development of custom websites using both proprietary (BlenderCMS) and WordPress CMS.
- Experience building WordPress Custom themes with Advanced Custom Fields and Plugins integration.
- Experience designing and developing eCommerce stores from scratch using Miva Merchant and Shopify.
- Domain and Hosting management.

RECENT PROJECTS

WordPress Projects

- https://www.omniqualityliving.ca/
- https://www.carbonneutralltd.com
- https://site.sigmalithiumresources.com/
- https://tankerservices.teekay.com/

Custom PHP Projects

- https://www.centurylithium.com/
- https://www.bmcms1.com/staging/sangramoller2.com/
- https://www.bmcms1.com/staging/kenorlandminerals.com
- https://evoterminals.com/
- https://plantinghopecompany.com/

WORK HISTORY

Web Developer

Blender Media, Vancouver, Canada Jul, 2021 to Present – 2 yr.

- Development of custom websites on BlenderCMS and WordPress with industry and company standards.
- Participate in meetings and breakout sessions to provide perspectives, ideas and solutions.
- Optimizing existing website components.

Web Developer

IMTEK Environmental Co, Alpharetta, USA Jul, 2019 to Jun, 2021 – 2 yrs.

- Development, Customization, and feature integration on various platforms like WordPress, Shopify and Miva Merchant.
- Maintaining websites with content updates, feature enhancements, website speed optimization and regular store updates.
- Email template and newsletters development in HTML for campaigns.

Educator (Asst. Professor) PGGCG, Sec-11, Chandigarh, IND (gcg11.ac.in) 2009 to 2019 – 10 yrs.

Conducted training programs/lectures on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C++ programing to undergraduate computer science students.

Jr. Web Developer Web Store Engineers, Noida, IND 2008 - 2009 – 1 yr.

- WordPress Blog development and UI customization.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create product landing pages and checkout process on Miva Merchant ecommerce platform.